









Skilled Frontend Developer with overall 6+ years of working experience in Software Development field and 3+ years of experience in creating user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Proficient in React and Angular. Strong understanding of responsive design and cross-browser compatibility.

CONTACT

+91-8295590454

atulmittal0795@gmail.com

Bangalore, India

https://atul-mittal-07.github.io/portfolio/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/atu
lmittal07/

https://github.com/atul-mittal-07

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Computer Science and Engineering Kurukshetra University, 2016

SKILLS

List all skills you have mastered throughout your career.

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React
- Git
- Angular
- Parcel
- JEST
- Unit testing
- SAP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer III

Walmart | 2020 - Present

As an Individual contributor, I worked on creating Progressing Web Apps for Warehouse Management Solutions for Manufacturing (Walmart US Omni Tech Business).

- 1. Contributed to the development of Issue Management Application. An in-house product and web-app created in React to record, track and close the issues that happen in the Manufacturing Plants of Walmart during product movements. This has improved the overall MTTR by 40% in the first quarter of its go-live and with many features in the future this is going to increase further. Various regions like US, CAM Countries (Costa Rica, Guatemala, El Salvador) were served using this App.
- 2. Contributed to writing Unit Test Cases for Smart Production Planner Application using JEST framework as part of Engineering Excellence initiative. This caused reduced production bugs, removal of unwanted code, increased code coverage, reducing code smells and many more.
- 3. Created suite of apps for Trim Operations in Meat Plant of Walmart which has given business of \$10MN/annum. These apps were created using Angular/Ionic Framework. Also contributed to applications like Rework, integrating ServiceNow with WMS Solutions.

Software Developer

Mobile Programming LLC (client-SAP Labs) | 2019 - 2020

Contributed to Demand Signal Management Suite of Applications.

This is a product suite developed by SAP for the manufacturing industries in order to forecast the future demand, harmonize the various products under same category, managing BOMs.

Customers like PepsiCo, Beiersdorf, Nestle and many more use this product on daily basis.

Primarily worked in SAP OData to create Backend REST APIs that cater the requests for the harmonization results and various other product information to the frontend.

Software Engineer

Tricon Infotech (client-SAP Labs) | 2018 - 2019

Contributed to Globalization Services Business

Created many reports and other utilities in S4 Logistics to be used by SAP. It was a short stint, but I was able to work on various advance SAP programming concepts like AMDP, CDS Views that were proved to be helpful in creating SAP OData REST APIs.

SVC Info Developer -1B

DXC.Technology | 2016-2018

Worked for COMPASS team wherein I was responsible for designing, coding and laying out the invoices and purchase orders that were used for client Hewlett-Packard.

Created few SAP ABAP based POCs in order to make developer's development lifecycle much easier. This POC was adopted, and it could save 3 months of development effort to just 3 weeks. Received many accolades during my tenure.